cholainsurance.com 2016-11-26

# Privacy Policy - Cholamandalam MS General Insurance Company Limited

Home Privacy Policy

We value you as a customer / user of our website and respect your right to privacy. Chola MS is committed to ensuring that privacy of the information you provide to us while accessing our site is protected. This policy sets out how Chola MS uses and protects the information you provide when you access the site and is subject to changes from time to time. Hence we request you to go through the policy every time you access the site. To help us in protecting your privacy, you should maintain absolute secrecy of your login ID and password, if any, provided to you in connection with your access / account with [www.cholainsurance.com](http://www.cholainsurance.com/) or its related sites / portals and should not share it with anybody.

It is recommended that customers choose their passwords carefully such that no unauthorized access is made by another person. To make the password difficult and complex for others to guess, you may choose a combinations of alphabets, numbers, special characters like $.#,@,* etc.

## **Collecting your personal information**

### **When do we collect?**

We may collect the information you provide when you:

  * Request information from our website
  * Use online tools and calculators
  * Apply online for our products/ services/ jobs etc.
  * Conduct any transaction online

### **What do we collect?**

We generally collect information such as your name, date of birth, gender, job title, contact address including email address, contact number and any other information as given in the registration page of our website. In case you are transacting online for our services / products, we will collect financial information such as credit card number and expiration date through the payment gateway of the credit card company or the Internet banking service of your bank. We store this information for our records as well as authentication purposes. We also collect information such as beneficiary name, address and your relationship to the beneficiary when you buy a policy from us. This is required to maintain a record of your beneficiary details for your insurance with us. 

If you choose to use our referral service to tell a friend about our site, we will ask you for your friends name and e-mail address. Your friend will automatically be sent a one-time e-mail inviting him or her to visit the website.

## **Use of your personal information**

### **Why do we collect?**

We require this information to understand your needs and provide you better service and in particular for the following:

  * Internal record keeping
  * Allow you to access specific account information
  * We may use the information provided by you to customize your visit to the website by displaying appropriate content at our judgment and discretion
  * To send you information about other products and services offered by Chola MS or its affiliates including promotional e-mails, new products, special offers, or any other information which we think maybe interesting to you
  * To contact you for policy reminder notices, claims processing and to keep you updated on the insurance sector and Chola MS through our newsletters. In event you do not wish to receive such information, you may unsubscribe through the facility in the email message you receive
  * We may also use the information for conducting surveys, market research purposes
  * We may contact you by phone, mobile, e-mail or fax 

**Log Files**

As is true of most websites; we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files. This information includes internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and click stream data. 

We use this information, which does not identify individual users, to analyze trends, to administer the site, to track users' movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. 

IP addresses are tied to personally identifiable information to help us customize your visit to our website so that you like the experience. However, we would like to reiterate that this information is not shared with third parties, for their promotional purposes, except as provided under "Disclosure of Information" clause. 

### **Use of Cookies**

We store a cookie on your computer when you visit our website. A cookie is a small text file that is stored on a user's computer for record-keeping purposes. The primary purpose of these cookies is to analyze how users move within our website. Our cookies lets you view customized pages while transacting with us. Our cookies do not have confidential or personally identifiable information. Since, we use session ID cookies; they do not track a user after leaving our website. A session ID cookie expires when you close the browser. It is required if you want to buy a policy online from us. We also use analytic tools to track visitor traffic on website. 

Some of our business partners such as chat support use cookies on our site. We have no access to or control over these cookies. This privacy statement covers the use of cookies by [www.cholainsurance.com](http://www.cholainsurance.com/ "cholainsurance") only and does not cover the use of cookies by any third parties.

You can choose to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies. But you can modify your browser setting to decline cookies as per your preference.

## **Controlling your personal information**

You may choose to restrict the collection or use of your personal information in the following way:

  * if you have previously agreed to us using your personal information for direct marketing purposes, you may change your mind at any time by emailing us at [customercare@cholams.murugappa.com](mailto:customercare@cholams.murugappa.com) or by writing to us at Customer Care, Chola MS General Insurance Co. Ltd., Hari Nivas Towers First Floor, #163, Thambu Chetty Street, Parry's Corner, Chennai - 600 001.

### **Disclosure of Information**

Subject to the other terms contained herein, we will not disclose your personal information to any third parties or affiliates for their promotional purposes, unless acting under a good faith belief that such action is necessary to: 

  * Conform to any statutory or legal requirements or comply with legal process or judicial orders
  * Protect, enforce and defend our rights or property
  * Protect our interests or interests of Murugappa Group Companies 

We may also use your personal information for the purposes of providing you with any services and service-related activities. In this regard, it may be necessary to disclose your personal information to one or more, sub-contractors, service providers (e.g. Third Party Administrators for Cashless Hospitalization, National Do Not Call Registry for filtering before Call related activities, other service providers) of Chola MS providing services linked to Insurance sector to fulfill your requests.

The Customer authorises Chola MS to exchange, share, part with all information related to the details and transaction history of the Customers to its affiliates / banks / financial institutions / credit bureaus / agencies / participation in any telecommunication or electronic clearing network as may be required by law, customary practice, credit reporting, statistical analysis and credit scoring, verification or risk management and shall not hold Chola MS liable for use or disclosure of this information. 

With your consent, we may share your information with our Group companies for offering their products/ services. In case you do not want to be solicited for any such services/ goods you may please indicate so.

We use service providers to fulfill some of the service requests on this site including live chat, third party administrators for cashless claims and health checkup and motor surveyors for vehicle inspection. We do not share, or sell your personal information to third parties. These service providers are not allowed to use your information for their promotional purposes. 

## **Updating your personal information**

If you need to update your personal information or there is any change in the personal information, or if you no longer desire our service, you may update or delete it by making the change on our registration page; email to [customercare@cholams.murugappa.com](mailto:customercare@cholams.murugappa.com); by contacting us by telephone at Toll Free 1800 200 5544 or by post to Customer Care, Chola MS General Insurance Co. Ltd., Hari Nivas Towers First Floor, #163, Thambu Chetty Street, Parry's Corner, Chennai - 600 001. 

### **Security**

The security of your personal information is important to us. When you enter sensitive information such as credit card number on our registration or order forms, we encrypt that information using secure socket layer technology (SSL).

We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and once we receive it. We also generally accepted industry practices to protect the privacy of your data as it is processed through our internal systems. No method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure, however. Therefore, while we strive to use commercially acceptable means to protect your personal information, we do not guarantee its absolute security. 

### **Retention of private data**

We shall be holding your data in our systems for the period that you are our customer. However, regulatory requirements may require that the data be stored for an extended period. In such cases, we will be forced to retain your information even though you are no longer our customer.

**Links to other sites**

Our website may contain links to other sites and / or portals on the Internet. While we intend to link only to such sites that share our high standards and respect for privacy, you should note that we do not control them and we are not responsible for the content or the privacy practices employed by such other sites. Hence you can hold us responsible for the protection and privacy of the information you provide whilst visiting these sites and these sites are not governed by our privacy policy. 

Please be aware that websites that have links from our site may collect personally identifiable information about you. This privacy statement does not cover the information and disclosure practices of those websites. When you leave our site, please read the privacy statements of each and every other site that collects personally identifiable information.

### **Business Transitions**

In the event Chola MS undergoes a business transition including merger, acquisition by another company, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, your personally identifiable information will likely be among the assets transferred. You will be notified via [email] [prominent notice on our website for 30 days] of any such change in ownership or control of your personal information.

### **Grievance Redressal**

While, we will strive to ensure you do not have any grievance, in case you have any concern or grievance, you may address the same to the Chief Grievance Officer, whose contact details have been published on our website.
